Private Dawes, report to the OC.
Relax, Dawes.
Bit cold out there, isn't it?
Yes, sir, tater's, sir.
You'd better go and pack
your sun cream, Dawes.
You're off to Afghan
and it's 47 degrees.
Battle casualty replacement.
You've done well on your
mission-specific training,
so you've got tonight fo
say goodbye to your family.
It's not going to
be easy, Dawes.
You're serving your country.
Do yourself proud.
Brize Norton, 1100
hours tomorrow.
You're to report to a
Corporal Kinders and be
attached to his section,
under Captain James.
First impressions are important.
Make the right one.
Private Dawes?
Yes, Corporal.
Welcome to the Under Fives.
Right, Dawes, you
are with 2 Section.
Double in and join them.
Can it really take you
massive cockwombles
this long to get in your sections
for a bloody photograph?
What are you laughing at, Medic?
"Cockwomble," sir.
For the benefit of our alleged
new medic, who are we?
The Under Fives, sirl
And why do you think
we're called that, Medic?
I don't know, sir.
Well, take a look.
They look young, sir?
And every one of
them is in my charge.
So if you can't cut it as our
medic and part of the team,
I have no hesitation in
lobbing you out of the plane.
- Is that understood?
- Yes, sir.
War Rages On
♪ The war rages on
4 You'll be at my side
♪ Through it all
4 Through hardships unseen
♪ We still survive
♪ Fortified
- I love a medic, me.
- Cos he's sick in the head.
He'll need you, poppet.
Pleased to make your
acquaintance. I'm Mansfield Mike.
- Although I'm not actually from Mansfield.
- Yeah, he is!
No, I'm not. I'm
from Derby, actually.
If it ain't my "Friday night round the
back of the Indian takeaway in Guildford"!
Oh, bollocks.
We were bound to meet again at
some point. That's the army for you.
You call me "Round the
back of the Indian takeaway"?
Only for shorthand.
I was going to text you back but we
weren't allowed phones at Catterick.
You've got something
on your chin.
Oh, it's just a bit of bullshit.
I bet you don't remember
what they call me.
I do, actually.
It's on my phone. "Smurf."
Cos you look like one.
No, I don't. I'm
bunk-up material, me.
I could have had any of
your section but I chose you.
Oh, I'm so proud.
Listen, don't say anything
to the others, yeah?
You're an idiot.
You don't want
me to tell the lads?
What happened that night, it was a
one-off. I was pissed out of my nut.
So you don't want
me to tell anyone?
You'd better not. First
impressions and all that.
I don't know if I'm comfortable
not telling my comrades the truth.
Well, I'm one of your comrades
now, so you'd better not let me down.
I'll just say I was on my phase
two, went to Pirbright for the rugby...
- met you and some girls and had a laugh.
- Well, it's the truth.
- Behind the takeaway.
- No, don't you dare.
Lads, mate of mine...
Cockney... Goon.
but all right.
- Happy?
- Ecstatic, you Welsh wanker.
Oh, ho-ho.
Cheeky.
Right, hour outside Bastion.
All don your full protective
clothing including helmets.
Look at that. Oh, my God.
They got a Costa Coffee.
They ain't even got one
of them in Basildon, Baz.
We got two as it happens
because Baz Vegas is paradise!
They got a Nando's?
They best have a Nando's or I'm
going home. I love Nando's, man.
He wanted to get a Nando's
tattoo when we was on basic!
- Don't tell everyone our secrets!
- Sorry, bruv.
Look at the size of the sun!
Loads bigger than
the England sun.
I'm going to need more
than factor 50 out here.
I'll tell you that for nothing.
Left, right, left, right, left.
Section, halt!
Right turn!
Platoon... platoon, ‘tion!
Welcome to Afghanistan.
You'll be here at Camp Bastion
for a few days" assimilation.
And then you are to be
deployed on a mission.
You have an excellent captain,
on his fourth tour of Afghanistan.
So you will listen and follow
his instructions to the letter.
Do well, apply yourselves
and you'll have a good tour.
Mansfield... Beautifull
Well within our price range, eh?
I don't know about you, mate.
I booked the presidential suite.
- Now I've got his stinky feet in my face.
- Fellas!
I'm leading a PT
session at 0530.
Make sure you hydrate tonight
and first thing in the morning.
Any of you helmets not on
top form and giving me 100%
will get my new regulation combat
boot six-lace-holes up your arses.
Best recruit at Catterick,
one pace forward.
Now, did you pass
geography at school, Dawes?
- No, sir.
- No.
Did you, Smurf?
Oh, yes, sir.
Good.
Then you can show our Doris
where the female quarters are.
This...is stags only.
- See you later, doc.
- Come on, Dawes. Get your stuff together.
You think I can't
manage my own kit?
Just trying to be nice.
"Best recruit at Catterick”.
What, the Captain say that to
you every time he talks to you?
He loves me. Everyone loves me.
I'm the life and soul, pal.
Dunno if I can put up with
six months of your bollocks.
Are you that pissed
off the captain likes me?
Maybe I don't want
that Rupert to like me.
Find your own quarters.
What?
He's a better person
than you'll ever be.
Don't worry about Smurf.
Looking for the female quarters?
Come on.
- It's a bit bloody hot, innit?
- You'll get used to it.
Dump your kit. That
bed's free next to mine.
I'm Molly, by the way.
Jackie.
You've arrived
on a killer hot day.
It's like walking
through treacle.
So you know Smurf, then?
I knew his twin brother.
He was killed on Herrick 15.
- You're joking?
- James was his Captain too.
That's why Smurf won't
hear a bad word about him.
I just called him a Rupert.
Smurf's brother Geraint
got shot in the neck on patrol.
James crawled about 200m on his
belly to get him and bring him back.
He weren't leaving him
as a trophy for the Taliban.
He'd do the same for you.
Let's hope he don't have to.
We'll get something
to eat later.
- They got a Nando's?
- Pizza Hut any good?
Gotta be better
than rations, eh?
It'll be worth it, trust me.
- Can't we phone up for a delivery?
- You can! Serious.
They got this little bloke
that bombs around on a bike.
Be quicker just to
grab one now, though.
You don't wanna be eating junk food
before a Captain James PT session!
We're off to the healthy tent.
I'll still be running while you're
breathing out of your arse.
Obsessing about my arse again?
Don't ask.
Six injured. MERT's bringing them in
now. All medical personnel to the hospital.
- Come on.
- Me?
You're "medical", aren't you?
Right, let's get him inside.
Molly, get on this stretcher.
Molly!
Soldier vs. IED.
Left below knee missing,
right above, tissue damage.
Unstable catastrophic
haemorrhage.
Slide.
Massive wound to lower back.
I need surgical access. Let
me know when that's happened.
We need blood stat.
Still losing blood!
Can we get a pelvic X-ray
and a fast scan, please?
- We're clear for chest X-ray.
- Temperature 36.
Come on, focus.
We're losing him!
Sort yourself out.
You all right, Moll?
I really thought my
training would kick in.
It will do. Don't
worry about it.
Will he make it? The marine.
Got a better chance
here than anywhere else.
The state of him, Jackie...
Get some shut-eye.
If only!
[tll be all right.
Private Dawes.
Well, I suppose we should be
grateful you're not wearing your stilettos.
It's full kit, Dawes.
Yes, sir.
Left, right, left,
right, left, right.
One, two, three, four.
Are we all acclimatised
to the conditions?
Sir.
Right, we sprint
the last 50. Gol
Smurf, hit the deck now!
Medic, man down!
Left leg blown off below the
knee. What are you going to do?
Come on, what
are you going to do?
You're really going to let him bleed out
while you gasp for air like a puffer fish?
Come on, Dawes!
This isn't Call Of Duty
on the Play Station.
Someone stands on an IED,
there's a life to save. Get it?
Come on, what
are you going to do?
Come on, Dawes.
Smurf, get up.
- Who are we?
- The Under Fives.
- The Under Fives!
Now get yourselves
showered now. Double away.
He could have died just then.
Please don't tell me we've got the only
medic who can't stand the sight of blood.
Relax, lads.
We're out of Bastion
in the morning
and headed to our special
little Forward Operating Base.
This will be our home
for the immediate.
When we arrive at
the village, we will link
up with a small tally of
Afghan National Army.
Three's a small Taliban
cell destabilising the area.
Lovely.
- Any questions?
- No, sir.
We need the locals to like us
and more importantly to trust us.
Nobody let me down.
Right, our task on the
ground is to support,
assist and advise the
Afghan National Army
with patrols around the
general area of the FOB
and facilitate the local children's
safe passage to their school.
Sound easy?
Lollipop men with guns.
Then get your head
out of your arse, Dawes.
There is no such thing as
an easy mission out here.
Right, you'll be flown out in
your sections 0400 tomorrow.
So tonight I need you all
to have seen the medic.
It's like speed-dating, Dawes.
One minute each, then
sod them off out of it.
Sit up!
Nice one, Dawes.
Lads, sort yourselves out.
Single file. You're
in your own time now.
Boys!
- Ready, Dawes?
- Yes, Corporal.
Right, Nude-Nut, in.
Oh. What's all that about?
I cut myself shaving and I know
how much you hate the sight of blood.
Do you feel fit?
Any injuries at all?
- You can sit down.
- No, I best not. Fit and well.
Shall I send the next person in?
- Was there nothing?
- No. See you.
Boys giving you a hard time?
I just feel like I keep
getting off on the
wrong foot. I keep
saying the wrong things.
Have you seen the way that
Captain James looks at me?
We're all trying
to prove ourselves.
You'll be fine.
I promise you.
I proper froze in that hospital.
You'll be fine.
It takes time and...
Sounds like it was a nasty one.
I'm worried that I
won't be able to cut it.
We're all worried we
Anyone who says
they're not is bullshitting.
Jackie told me about
your brother, Geraint.
When the Taliban jackpotted him,
James said he heard a cheer go up.
I'm sorry, Smurf.
I'm not being...stupid
or nothing, Molls,
but these people,
the Taliban and that,
they're not like us.
They're heartless.
You'll be all right, mate.
They laughed as he
lost his life out there.
He lost his life for
our country, Moll.
I don't want him to
have died in vain.
- What does that mean?
- [t means...
I'm going to make
sure he didn't die in vain.
You got piles, Smurf?
Then you don't need
to sit down, do you?
You all right, fella?
In case any of you were in
any doubt, this is the real deal.
The next six months will
define the rest of our lives.
There will be moments on this
tour that you will never forget.
Both good and bad.
It's not about looking
after number one,
it's about looking after numbers
two to 12 in your section.
That way you will always have
11 people walching your back.
It's why the British
Army can never lose.
It is what separates
us from the enemy.
This mission is about
hearts and minds.
We want fo leave this place
in a better state than we find it
Stay focused.
Stay alert Stay alive.
The day you are less than 100%
focused is the day shit happens.
Hello, you.
Hearts and minds, Dawes.
You don't wanna be
talking to the little bleeders.
-Eh?
- Dickers.
Oh, they might look
sweet when they're little
but they all grow up
with one aim, to kill us.
I think she was
just being friendly.
Straight back to tell some
insurgent everything about us.
It's their way.
Fuel To Fire
4 Do you want me on your mind
4 Or do you want me to go on?
4 I might be yours
as sure as I can say
♪ Be gone, be far away
Water, boys.
Throw it over there.
Oh, comedy boys.
All right, handsome?
What happened?
Someone set fire to your face
and beat it out with a golf shoe?
What are you going
to do, shoot me?
0i, oi.
What's all that about?
That $10-Taliban was
giving me the evils.
Behave, will you?
He ain't Taliban.
He's one of us.
All right, then,
boys. First patrol.
All right, lads, all those years of
training, it's about this moment.
Yeah. I hope there's contact.
Come on, let's be having you,
before the sun gets his hat on.
Captain Azizi, let's go.
A magazine of 30 rounds. Load.
Hello, girl.
Hello, you.
There you go, little one.
You stay?
Pen. Pen.
Pen!
How was that?
Thought there might
be a bit more...action, sir.
Were they watching
us, do you reckon, sir?
Without a doubt, Baz.
After just one patrol you've
become their ace of spades,
the Taliban's most wanted
man after Prince Harry.
My mum always tells
me I look like Prince Harry.
The kids will come up to
you, but don't be distracted.
The ones on bikes by the trees to
the west could have been dickers.
What were they thinking, Dawes?
That we're at our
most vulnerable.
Why?
Well, we're finding our feet,
we don't know the terrain.
Right.
2 Section going
out again at 1300.
Everyone go and get some scoff.
You not hungry, Dawes?
I'm just going to wait for
the ruck to die down, sir.
Sir... Spit it out, Dawes.
Well, it's just...
as a medic, I'm a bit worried that
Smurf's in the right frame of mind.
Why's that?
All that with his brother must
have fragged with his head a bit.
Well, he's an excellent soldier.
He knows what he's doing.
It's just that...
he seemed a bit...
I dunno, harsh, let's
say, with an ANA bloke.
It's just a bit of early
tour dick-waving.
Always happens.
We're on tour!
Looks like you're
going to take off like ET.
Whoa, speaking of which...
Pen! Pen!
Dawesy!
We're all waiting at the gate.
No time to put your face on.
Can't see your pen-girl.
I brought some
with, just in case.
They can't even read or write, so
God knows why they need pens.
Maybe they wanna
learn to read and write.
It's mad how much we
take for granted, isn't it?
You're not going to start getting all
profound on me, are you, Dawesy?
No matter how cute they are when they're
little, they'll still grow up to hate you.
Doesn't have to be like
that. If we're nice to them...
- Nice?
- Well, what are you going to be?
Contact left! Contact left!
Take cover!
See what I mean, Molls?
Those fuckers have spilt
my family blood out there.
Did anyone see
where that came from?
I can't see anything.
Two in the compound
wall behind me.
Keep your heads fucking down.
Think it was from
the compound ahead.
I ain't got a skin what you're
on about. I can't see nothing!
- You sure?
- They are targeting the female.
They got eyes on us,
then, so keep down!
Come on then, you
mugs, let's have yal
Contact 200 metres ahead.
Four shots. Single shooter, sir.
- Have you got eyes on him?
- No, sir.
Interpreter says they're
targeting the female.
Get back inside, now!
Right, one at a time,
fucking sprint back into base.
Rest of you, eyes
on that far compound.
First man, go!
They know there's
a female medic here.
Move!
- Gol - Moving.
- Move!
- Moving.
Dawes, you're next.
- I can't do it, Smurf.
- Of course you can.
They're after me.
They ain't going to get
you. I'm going to get them.
They see you come out of this
ditch, the wankers will appear.
I'll blow their
shitty heads off.
Now get up and run!
I can't, Smurf. Just
leave without me.
Dawes, what are you
pissing about at? Go!
Just sorting the med kit!
You've got to go, Molly.
- They'll shoot me.
- No, they won't. I'll shoot them.
I need you guys
out of this ditch now!
Contact ahead! I see the tosser!
What the hell are you
doing, Smurf? Get down now!
Get down, Smurfl Get down!
Now, Molly! Fucking run!
Fucking run!
No-one's coming
out of there tonight.
Are you sure you saw something?
I didn't see anything.
It was like Call Of
Duty for a minute, boys.
Unbelievable!
- I wanna have another go at them, mate!
- Come on!
I haven't seen you run so fast
since Dirty Doreen tried to grope youl
- Did you see me run?
- You run a mile before you buy a pint!
I am never ever in my lifetime gonna
be able to work at Foot Locker again.
I am telling you now.
Have they got a Foot
Locker in Mansfield?
I'm from Derby, man!
What have we just learnt?
What have we just learnt?!
Every time we step outside this
compound, you need to be totally alert.
Medic.
I need you to have
a look at my blisters.
Yes, sir.
What do you reckon?
Well, they stink, sir,
with all due respect.
His behaviour when he was unloading his
weapon into that compound was reckless
and unprofessional.
Who, sir?
Maybe he was "in the
wrong frame of mind".
Sir.
Did you see anyone, Dawes?
He didn't eyeball anyone.
Say there'd been some
children playing inside.
It doesn't bear thinking about.
Did you see an insurgent, Dawes?
He's a good lad, sir. He's got
a lot of stuff he's dealing with.
You don't deal with it whilst
you're carrying a lethal weapon.
He's all right.
He just saved my
arse in that ditch.
I knew I didn't need new boots.
There was nothing
wrong with my old ones.
They'll wear in.
Let me dress your blisters and you can
get back to running us round the compound.
- Well, let's see how good a medic you are.
- The nuts, sir.
Smurf.
A word.
Uh-oh.
Right, Fingers...
Oh, yes, sir.
Give that to
Dangleberries, would you?
Dawes, mail.
Come on.
- She likes a male, sir.
- Ohl
Ow!
I was about to say, "Has anyone
noticed there's no grass in Afghan?"
- But I spoke too bloody soon.
- Ohl
Boss man. Major Beck on the net.
Right, Fingers. You take over.
And no arsing around.
- I am the only one allowed to arse around.
- Sir.
Right...
Oh, Baz Vegas.
Ooh. Smells like lavender,
bro, and it's a man's handwriting.
- Something you not telling us?
- Sump oil, you dick!
And it's my dad's handwriting!
I know you've told the others
that I'm some sort of dirty old slag.
If the cap fits...
Get out. Get out or I
will seriously kill you!
That is a shit
thing to do, Smurf.
Now no-one can even look at me.
You brought it on yourself.
There's only two things
I don't like about you.
Your face.
Going to James and
stabbing me in the back!
It weren't like that.
You think I'm mad.
Out of control. A liability!
He called me in and
he sat me down...
Maybe anything I said was
cos I was worried about you.
And I didn't say
anything like that.
But you said something, though.
I saved your arse in
that ditch out there!
I know you did. And now you've
gone and ruined my entire tour.
Fuck you, Smurf.
You already have.
Blue Angel
♪ Blue angel
♪ It's the memory of your warmth
♪ That keeps me alive
4 When I'm burning
4 And my world's closing in
4 Ooh, I'm on fire
As you were, guys.
Right, listen in.
The proposed ANA
checkpoint will be here.
Based in an old compound the Russians
commandeered a few decades ago,
so we'll help Captain Azizi give
it a bit of a Kirstie make-over.
Dried riverbed below
and across from the riverbed we have what
intel reliably inform us is a minefield.
They think they're
old Russian mines but
nonetheless capable
of blowing your socks off.
Any questions?
Is everything all right, Dawes?
They're sending
me to Coventry, sir.
That is worse than Helmand!
Why are they doing that?
Cos of what I said
to you about Smurf.
I have to get everyone
through this tour.
That's my job and
nothing else matters.
Yes, sir.
And therefore
I'm grateful to you.
Despite what they say, you did the
right thing to tell me your concerns.
And for what it's worth,
I think I make you right.
I'm a tad worried too.
Thanks, sir.
Glad to see they're cracking on.
What are they going to do
when we pull out completely?
It's not for us to
worry about, Dawes.
We do what we're told till we get
back on that plane to Brize Norton.
This whole place
is going to go...
I follow my orders and
I trust those higher in
the chain of command
to see the bigger picture.
- Really?
- Absolutely.
It's what we have to believe
in and so I believe in it.
I suggest you do the same.
Minefield's to the west
below the riverbed.
Be aware.
There we go.
What's your name?
How do you say "What's
your name?" in Pashto?
Have I said it wrong?
- What's she saying?
- Her name. Bashira.
Ah, Bashira. That's
a lovely name.
I'm Molly.
Molly.
How old are you, Bashira?
-11.
-11?
That's the best
age. Stay 11 for ever!
Tell her I've got a sister
who's a similar age in London.
Tell her that she can be my
sister while I'm here if she wants.
What's that thing they use
in golf, for hitting the ball on?
Tee.
Milk, two sugars, please.
Thank you very much.
I wouldn't mind a cuppa.
Relax, lads.
Make sure you're
loaded up on water.
Dehydration's an
absolute bitch out here.
Check your piss.
Make sure it's not too yellow.
Fingers, I want you
to set up a kitchen.
Smurf, you're on latrine duties.
- Set up an area.
- Sir.
Well away from
my kitchen, please.
And we need a spot to
burn the silver shit bags.
Nude-Nut.
Dawes, I want you to set up a
treatment facility with an ANA medic.
Captain Azizi, I need you to
clear those kids away right now.
That little wanker is a dicker.
What are you talking about?
No, go on, say
something, I dare you.
All right, I will say
something. That kid is
spotting for the Taliban
and reporting back.
She's just a kid,
Smurf. Chill out.
Yeah, a kid who goes back and
tells the Taliban exactly where we are.
What are you up to?
I guess I'm lucky the
army weren't called in
to make sure I went
to school in East Ham.
You didn't go?
Could you tell?
Still, you don't need
GCSEs out here, do you?
It's a good job I ain't
got any, then, sir.
Man down! Man down!
Man down!
- What's happened?
- I don't know.
Smurf saw something and
went down the riverbed, sir.
- Across the riverbed?
- Anyone got eyes on?
200 metres. Half
left. Behind the bridge.
- That's Smurfl - It's
the bloody minefield!
What are you doing
in a bloody minefield?
I've been shot.
I'm pumping blood!
Smurf, what direction
was your contact?
- I'm pumping blooa!
- He's got the Vallon with him.
He took it down with him.
He needs a medic!
I can get to him, sir. I
know my mine clearing drill.
No fucking way. Wait out.
- Sir, he's losing blood. I can get to him.
- Wait out.
Just because I'm a female, sir,
I don't want special treatment.
I'm the medic, I should go.
I'm pissing blood!
I can't stop it!
Dangleberries,
Brains, with me now.
Move. Move, move.
Move.
Eyes out.
Let's go, fellas, keep eyes on.
- Has anyone seen the enemy?
- Can't see him.
Molly.
Stay calm, Smurf.
Brains! Dangles!
Smurfl
Smurfl It's pissing out of me.
Smurf, I'm on my way.
Talk to me.
Alpha 3.0 Bravo. 9 Lino.
Roger. So far. Over.
Stay calm, Smurf.
Where are you hit?
Top of the leg. High.
Groin.
Can you get a
tourniquet round it?
I can't get it on. I's too high.
Smurf?
Are you all right, Dawes?
Talk to me, Smurf.
Nude-Nut, Fingers. Cover
them as they're moving.
- Yes, Corporal.
You're going to need a winch.
There is nowhere to land. I
repeat, there is nowhere to land.
- She ain't going to make it.
- Yes, she will, Fingers.
We'll make sure of it.
Smurfl Come on, Smurf. Get up.
Smurfl Talk to me, Smurfl
Smurfl Are you all right, Dawes?
Have you got eyes on
Smurf? He's gone quiet.
Talk to her, Smurf.
Come on, Smurf, you tit.
ETA, 30 seconds
on the MERT, sir.
Smurf?
- Smurf?
- Smurf, - Smurf, come onl
Dawes, have you got eyes on
Smurf? Speak to me. How is he?
Dawes!
- Moll?
- Dawes!
Dawes!
Molly?
Can anyone see her?
I've got eyes on.
She ain't moving, sir.
Contact explosion. Wait out.
Dawes!
Dawes, are you all right?
Dawes, talk to me.
I'm all right.
I'm all right, sirl
She's all right, she's OK!
- Come on, Moll!
- She's all right.
- Yes, Molly!
I can't believe I've
still got my legs.
Just you, Smurf.
Come on lad, come on.
- Eyes on, boys, eyes on. Cover her!
- I see her. I see her.
Moll, what's going on?
Smurf?
Smurfl
Smurf.
Come on, Smurf. Talk to me.
Smurf, come on. Talk to
me. I've come to save you.
Come on, Smurfl
Smurf. Oi, Smurf.
Stay with me. I'm gonna
get you out of here.
Please, please don't
die on me, you bell-end.
Dawes, how is he?
I need a helicopter.
I'm losing him.
Just stay with me,
Smurf. Keep talking.
Keep making noises for me, yeah?
That's it.
That's it, Smurf.
Sir, they can't land here.
It's mined to buggery.
They're gonna drop a winch.
Secure him to the winch
and they'll hoist him up.
I'm gonna have to
go up with him, sir.
- Absolutely no way.
- That's it.
There's a sniper.
You'll be a sitting target
dangling on the
end of a fucking rope.
No way!
Sir, the tourniquet's
not working. If I take
my fist out of his groin,
he's gonna bleed out.
Lucky I got here when I did, eh?
Come on, Smurf.
Dawes, do not go up on
that winch. That is an order!
I can't hear a thing, can you?
Am I going to die?
No. If you die, they're
all going to think it's
my fault. That ain't gonna
happen, OK, wanker?
Go on, girl!
Dawes, do not go up on
that winch. That is an order!
Do you hear me?
Dawes!
I doubt she can hear
a thing under that.
She goes up with him, the
sniper will pop her straight away.
Sitting ducks, guys.
Dawes. What do you think you are doing?
Get off that winch now. That is an order.
Dawes!
Oh, fuck.
Go on, Moll.
Yes, Molly! Yes, Molly!
Come on, Molly!
- 2 Section!
- Molly!
What she just did there
was stupid beyond belief!
She disobeyed a command
and put her life in danger.
Fingers, cover them as they're
moving up. Rest of you, eyes on.
It was also fucking awesome.
Told you you'd live.
Shit.
What?
I thought it was a dream.
That'll be the morphine.
Smurf, what the hell were you
doing in the middle of a minefield?
I saw someone...
I thought they were
planting an IED.
It was that kid of yours.
Bashira?
I went to take a look.
I thought there was
a path that was clear.
Yeah, and what happened?
I looked along the path
and right at the other end
there was this insurgent
pointing a rifle at my head.
Lucky he was a shit shot, then.
Molls.
Got transport to take you
to the helipad if you're quick.
OK.
Molls, I was a dickhead.
But I'm telling you,
I've learnt a big lesson.
Come here.
I'm going to get myself better
and I'm going to come back to you.
Come back to me?
To the platoon.
I'm going to make it up to
you cos I owe you everything.
Yeah, you do, you nut-bar.
I'll never let you down again.
I'll always be there for you.
Let Me Down Gently
♪ Let me down gently
♪ That's what I think I need
♪ But when you
let me down gently
♪ It still feels hard...
Sir.
If you think you're going to win
any plaudits for that foolhardy act,
you are 100% mistaken.
Yes, sir. Sorry, sir.
That's what my commanding officer said
to me when I retrieved Smurf's brother.
Sir?
Having said that, did you hear me
tell you not to go up on that winch?
No, sir.
Well done, Dawes.
Thank you, sir.
I'm not what Smurf said I was.
- I didn't deserve that.
- I know.
I might have slept with
a few people I regret...
We all have.
It's 2014, not 1914.
And don't let a bit of name-calling
put you off the task in hand.
You are an excellent medic,
you're proving yourself.
♪ She's one of the
lads She's one of the lads
♪ Molly Dawesy,
she's one of the lads
Thanks, you fuckmuppets!
Captivate You
Heavily armed insurgents are controlling
the area around the mountains and village.
Who's done this to your
face, Bashira? Is it your dad?
Something about
her smells a bit rotten.
Do not involve yourself
in the lives of the locals.
They must not become dependant on us
in any way, shape or form. Understand?
You must not go to the
mountains tomorrow.
She's trying to warn
me about something.
Either they're luring us in or
something else is going to happen.
Remember, stay focused,
stay alert, stay alive.
Down! RPG!
What are you doing?
Dawes, get down now!
4 And I will captivate you
4 With everything I've got
4 To bring the best out in you
♪ One strength, one heart
♪ Is all you need tonight
♪ Tonight, tonight, tonight